SAIF KHAN

Computer Science student specialized in Deep Learning and Software Engineering. 6+ years experience in native Android app development using Kotlin and Java languages. Skilled in mobile development, static web development and machine learning using various Python frameworks.



CONTACT

saifkhichi96@gmail.com

saifkhichi.com

@ saifkhichi96

in Muhammad Saif Ullah Khan

(D) 0000-0002-7375-807X

SKILLS

Programming

Python Kotlin Java HTML C JavaScript TeX Hack

Databases

MySQL (with PHP), SQLite (for Android), NoSQL databases like Firebase Realtime Database / Firestore and MongoDB..

Software and Tools

Deep Learning (Py-Torch, scikit-learn), Image Processing (OpenCV, PIL, scikit-image), Visualization/Computing (Matplotlib, NumPy, SciPy), Advertisements/Analytics (Google Analytics, AdMob,AdSense, Crashlytics), Web Hosting/DNS Setup (e.g. GitHub Pages, Firebase Hosting, etc.).

Other Tools

Jekyll website generator, **Blender** for 3D modeling, **Unity** game engine.

Languages

English (Bilingual)
German (Basic (A2.1))
Urdu (Native)

WORK HISTORY

11/2021 - present

♥ German Research Center for Artificial Intelligence (DFKI)
Kaiserslautern. DE

1 09/2018 - 02/2019

Active Institute of Science, Arts and Technology (AISAT) Multan, PK Research Assistant

Software Developer and Graphics Designer

EDUCATION

🖰 2023 - present

Rheinland-Pfälzische Technische Universität Kaiserslautern-Landau (RPTU)
Kaiserslautern, DE PhD Student

2019 - 2022

♥ Technische Universität Kaiserslautern (TUK) *Kaiserslautern*, *DE* **Master of Computer Science**

2014 - 2018

National University of Sciences and Technology (NUST) Islamabad, Pakistan Bachelor of Software Engineering 3.78 CGPA (1.33 ECTS)

PUBLICATIONS/RESEARCH

Dataset M. Khan, D. Stricker, M. Afzal, (2022). Generating Synthetic RGB-D Datasets for Texture-less Surfaces Reconstruction. Proceedings of NeurIPS Track on Datasets and Benchmarks. (Pending)

Review M. Khan, D. Stricker, M. Afzal, (2022). 3D Reconstruction from a Single RGB Image using Deep Learning: A Review. Journal of Imaging. (Pending)

Dataset M. Khan, (2021). A novel segmentation dataset for signatures on bank checks. arXiv Preprint. http://doi.org/10.34740/KAGGLE/DS/1041694

Thesis M. Khan, B. Ahmad, M. Tariq, M. Malik, (2018). Signature Verification. NUST School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Sciences. http://doi.org/10.13140/RG.2.2.11002.24006/1

PROJECTS

- ▶ **RECatalyst** A collaborative tool for software project management and requirements specification as an Android application.
- ▶ Eduistein ☑ An online learning management system for smart schools in shape of an Android app, developed for a client in India.
- ▶ Acacia Joinery ☑ A mobile application to aid in customer requirements elicitation for an architectural firm based in Bellambi, Australia.
- ▶ IPRD Geotag ☑ A location-based remote work status monitoring Android app developed for PRD Jharkhand, India.
- ▶ **Tiled** ✓ Lightweight API for easily creating tilemaps in Android. It is useful for applications and games which need to display tile-based graphics.